So let's talk about the school that canceled me from speaking at Black graduation,
stating that they didn't have the budget to pay me, even though I said I would speak for free.
The school that canceled me from Black graduation is my alma mater, SUNY Purchase.
SUNY Purchase reached out to me, their Black graduation committee, to speak at Black graduation.
Now, some of you all may not know, but some schools will have a special graduation just for the Black students.
And I have spoken at several Black graduations.
Two years ago, SUNY Purchase asked me to come speak at their Black graduation.
Again, SUNY Purchase is my alma mater.
And again, I was the commencement speaker at my own graduation at SUNY Purchase.
So SUNY Purchase reached out to book me to come speak at their Black graduation.
In 2023, I spoke at Black graduation.
They also gave out an award in my name called the Amanda Seals Activism Award.
And the only thing I required that time was for them to get me from the city because I didn't live in New York at the time.
So I asked them to get me from the city because I was staying in the city.
Get me from the city up to the school.
The school is an hour away from the city.
When I got there, they had provided me with like hors d'oeuvres, you know, like a fruit plate, etc.
Which is standard.
Now, I spoke at the graduation.
We handed out the Amanda Seals Activism Award.
It was really honestly a beautiful experience.
And considering how much SUNY Purchase put me through at its school,
I felt like there was a certain kind of full circle moment happening.
So when they reached out again this year, we asked,
Oh, are you all handing out the Amanda Seals Activism Award?
And they said, Oh, we don't know anything about that.
Fine.
Well, we said, my representative told them,
Well, the only thing we would ask is that we get to hand out the award again.
Otherwise, Amanda will do it free of charge.
She then sent them my writer.
Let's talk about what a writer is.
A writer is basically like the hospitality requirements for somebody
when they are going to take part in an event, etc.
Some people's writers are out of this world.
Like Beyonce's writer includes like they have to put a new toilet seat in.
Like Jennifer Lopez's writer is like the entire room has to be white.
Like crazy shit like that.
Famously, I think it was the Rolling Stones or Van Halen,
one of these groups had a writer where it was like,
Oh, there can't be any green M&Ms.
Okay.
That's a writer.
I have purposely made my writer under $100.
My writer is literally a fruit plate, a vegetable plate,
some apple juice, some water, some tea,
and spicy nacho or sweet, sorry, sweet chili Doritos.
That's my writer.
Okay.
I have purposely made my writer affordable because one,
people don't be having money.
Two, I don't need all this extra shit.
But three and three, I do deserve to have some basic creature comforts when I'm coming to work.
We just got an email from them earlier today saying that we cannot afford you,
afford for you to come.
Oh, oh, oh, I'm leaving out.
I'm leaving out.
Even though I said I was going to speak for free,
they said, we're actually going to offer you $1,000.
So even though I said, I will speak for free,
they said, we will give you $1,000.
We said, okay.
The email that we received today is due to budgetary reasons,
we can no longer have you speak.
To which my representative replied, that doesn't make any sense.
What is the real reason?
Because to be quite honest, we haven't asked you for anything.
And now you're saying that it's budgetary reasons.
And for what it's worth, let me also add,
sending a writer, we always have people come back
and they may say something like, we can't afford all of the writer.
Is it okay if we just make sure to provide X, Y, Z?
Sure.
Even though, by the way, the can't afford is like,
what are we talking about?
The reason this live is called Know Your Worth
is because they then came back and said,
no, it really is because of the budget.
We cannot afford your writer.
So we just decided, I want you to hear this.
The budget is our real reason.
We unfortunately were not given enough money
to have Ms. Seals attend due to the requests made in the writer,
as well as among other things for the event
that we had to pay for, such as catering and decorations.
I don't know who their advisor is,
but they're doing a terrible job.
They're doing a terrible fucking job.
This is very embarrassing.
And the real reason, I believe, is they were told,
you cannot have Amanda Seals here
because it is SUNY purchase
and this is a wildly Zionist town.
To state that we had to make decorate,
we had to pay for catering and decoration
so we can't have you, icon, activist, advocate,
Amanda Seals, artist, intellectual, alumni.
And I, y'all know your value.
Know your worth.
Okay?
Know your value.
Know your worth.
The fact that these people are stating to me
with no issue, like in full chest,
we chose catering and decorations
over giving you a fruit plate
is wildly embarrassing.
So SUNY purchase and the Black graduation,
I would say, I don't wish,
I don't wish the graduation the best.
I think it's really disingenuous.
I think it's really disrespectful.
And I genuinely feel like
this is a representation of so many Black spaces
that simply just do not have any regard
for Black intellectuals.
They just don't.
You know, Howard University once told me,
well, we spent all our money on Lil Wayne,
so can you come speak for free?
And to be what it's worth,
and for what it's worth,
you're telling me that nobody could come up with $50?
Nobody could come up with $50?
For me?
So this is the kind of scenarios we're dealing with.
Um, again, I do not take any of this personal.
I do not take any of this as a reflection
of something I'm doing wrong.
I am also not in any way,
um, I want to be clear,
I'm not offended as if I am being,
I'm not offended at the disrespect.
Let me be clear.
I'm not offended.
I am more so,
I'm offended that this is how they're sending out
our Black students into the world.
This, this is the way that they are training up
Black students to go into the world
to protect the decorations
versus the substance.
And that's exactly the world that we're in
that has got us fucked up.
We care more about the decorations
than the substance.
And so to cut out something of so much value
as me sharing my wisdom,
my humor, and my intellect
for the preference of decorations
speaks volumes
as to what even the validity of this event is.
It's a decoration.
And to ask me to come
and then say,
and they've been in conversation for a month,
by the way,
to ask me to come
and then say,
we actually don't want you to come
within two weeks
of the event
during graduation season.
So for the record,
what if I had been asked
to speak somewhere else on that date
but turned it down
because I had already committed to them?
No regard for that.
This is how we're,
this is how we are behaving.
It is shameful, Yana Brooke.
And I am less concerned with,
you know,
I know people are telling me like,
rejection is God's protection.
My feelings aren't hurt.
Like, I'm not over here like,
oh man,
you know,
they were blessed to have me.
I was blessed to be in exchange
with young minds,
young black minds.
That's a,
that's a synergistic exchange.
So again,
I just want to say
SUNY purchased black graduation.
Better decisions should have been made.
Better guidance
should have been provided
to these students
by the administrators.
and
this is deeply disappointing
that this is how
you are treating
the folks
that we should be cherishing
in our communities.
Bing!
whoop!
Usually we have children
whoopin'
and who Shouldn't
spread that
as well.
When you're
there around
was a
husband
that
yeah,
that will
save
it.
awareness
and
what
you
know.
Like,
what's
a
thing
we
here I
tossed up
on the
slide
with
what's